MERT YAZİCİ

Izmir · 531 790 36 06 · yazici.mert.35@gmail.com www.mertyazici.dev · GitHub · Linkedin

SUMMARY

After graduating from high school, I started my professional career as an insurance sales consultant at Ediz Kurt Sigorta company. To support my business, I also started studying at Anadolu University, Department of Banking and Insurance, and graduated in 2013. After 4 years of work experience, I left my job here to continue my education and started studying at Dokuz Eylül University, Department Economics. During my second university education, I discovered my interest in the software field and started to focus on this field with individual studies. In 2021, I started my professional career in sofware as an SEO Consultant at Kriko Bilişim Company. In order to support my development, I started the relevant departments at Demokrasi University and Istanbul University. Currently, I am designing websites as a freelancer with the experience I have gained and my personal works.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Seo Consultant, Kriko Bilişim

2021 - 2023

- Provided consultancy services to major brands, focusing on e-commerce websites and achieving significant performance improvements for both B2B and B2C businesses.
- Executed comprehensive SEO strategies encompassing technical SEO and various other aspects of search engine optimization.
- Utilized industry-leading tools such as SEMrush, Searchmetrics, and Ahrefs to drive data-driven SEO campaigns.
- Developed and implemented on-page and off-page SEO strategies to enhance website visibility and organic traffic.
- Monitored and reported on SEO performance metrics, providing actionable insights for continuous improvement.
- Worked proficiently with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create landing pages and simple designed websites.

Sales Associate & Store Manager, Mamouth Shopping

2017 - 2020

• Managed customer relations and product procurement for the store.

Insurance Technical Specialist & Sales Consultant, Ediz Kurt Sigorta

2010 - 2014

• Issued and marketed insurance policies.

EDUCATION

Department of Banking and Insurance

2010 - 2013

Anadolu University

Department of Economics

2014 - 2019 (Incomplete)

Dokuz Eylül University

Department of Management Information Systems

2021 - 2023 (Incomplete)

Demokrasi University

Department of Web Design and Coding

2023 - Present

İstanbul University

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: CSS3, HTML5, JS, React, Vue, Next, WordPress, Screaming Frog, Searchmetrics, Semrush, Ahrefs, GSC, GA
- Languages: English (intermediate)
- Certifications:
- 1. Udemy Sıfırdan Projelerle Front-End ve React 18.x Öğren Hakan Yalçınkaya
- 2. IBM Cybersecurity Fundamentals
- 3. IBM Working in a Digital World: Professional Skills
- 4. Laba Eğitim ve Danışmanlık FrontEnd Developer Kursu Sinan Mutlu & Taha Selim Aksakal
- 5. Happy Academy 80 Saat A'dan Z'ye Dijital Pazarlama Eğitimi
- 6. Udemy Web Development HTML,CSS, Node , JavaScript, React, Angular, ASP.NET Core

MERT YAZİCİ

Karşıyaka İzmir · 531 790 36 06 · yazici.mert.35@gmail.com

www.mertyazici.dev · GitHub · Linkedin

ÖN YAZI

Liseden mezun olduktan sonra Ediz Kurt Sigorta acentesinde sigorta satış danışmanı olarak profesyonel iş hayatına başladım. İşimi desteklemesi için aynı zamanda Anadolu Üniversitesi Bankacılık ve Sigortacılık Bölümü'ne başladım ve 2013 yılında mezun oldum. 4 yıllık iş tecrübesinden sonra eğitimime devam etmek için buradaki işimden ayrıldım ve Dokuz Eylül Üniversitesi İngilizce İktisat Bölümü'ne başladım. İkinci üniversite eğitimim sırasında yazılım alanına olan ilgili keşfettim ve bireysel çalışmalar ile bu alana ağırlık vermeye başladım. 2021 yılında Kriko Bilişim Şirketi'nde Seo Danışmanı olarak yazılım alanında profesyonel iş hayatına başladım. Yazılım alanındaki gelişimimi desteklemek amacıyla Demokrasi Üniversitesi'nde ve İstanbul Üniversitesi'nde ilgili bölümlere başladım. Edindiğim tecrübeler ve kişisel çalışmalarım ile şu anda freelance olarak websitesi yapmakta ve kendimi geliştirmeye devam etmekteyim.

İŞ DENEYİMİ

Seo Consultant, Kriko Bilişim

2021 - 2023

- Büyük markalara danışmanlık hizmetleri sunarak, özellikle e-ticaret web sitelerine odaklanıp B2B ve B2C işletmeleri için önemli performans iyileştirmeleri elde ettim.
- Teknik SEO ve arama motoru optimizasyonunun çeşitli diğer yönlerini kapsayan kapsamlı SEO stratejileri uyguladım.
- SEMrush, Searchmetrics ve Ahrefs gibi sektör lideri araçları kullanarak veri odaklı SEO kampanyalarını yönettim.
- Web sitesi görünürlüğünü ve organik trafiği artırmak için sayfa içi ve sayfa dışı SEO stratejileri geliştirdim ve uyguladım.
- SEO performans metriklerini izleyip raporladım ve sürekli iyileştirme için uygulanabilir görüşler sundum.
- HTML, CSS ve JavaScript kullanarak landing page sayfalar oluşturdum.

Sales Associate & Store Manager, Mamouth Shopping

2017 - 2020

• Mağaza için müşteri ilişkilerini yönettim ve ürün tedarikini sağladım.

Insurance Technical Specialist & Sales Consultant, Ediz Kurt Sigorta

2010 - 2014

2010 - 2013

• Sigorta poliçelerini düzenledim ve pazarladım.

EĞİTİM

Bankacılık ve Sigortacılık

Anadolu Üniversitesi

Ekonomi 2014 - 2019

Dokuz Eylül Üniversitesi (Tamamlanmadı)

Yönetim Bilişim Sistemleri 2021 - 2023

Demokrasi Üniversitesi (Tamamlanmadı)

Web Tasarım ve Kodlama 2023 - Halen

İstanbul Üniversitesi

YETKİNLİK & SERTİFİKALAR

- Teknik Yatkınlıklar: CSS3, HTML5, JS, React, Vue, Next, WordPress, Screaming Frog, Searchmetrics, Semrush, Ahrefs, GSC, GA
- Yabancı Dil: English (intermediate)
- Sertifikalar:
- 1. Udemy Sıfırdan Projelerle Front-End ve React 18.x Öğren Hakan Yalçınkaya
- 2. IBM Siber Güvenlik Temelleri
- 3. Laba Eğitim ve Danışmanlık FrontEnd Developer Kursu Sinan Mutlu & Taha Selim Aksakal
- 4. Happy Academy 80 Saat A'dan Z'ye Dijital Pazarlama Eğitimi
- 5. Udemy Web Development HTML, CSS, Node, JavaScript, React, Angular, ASP.NET Core